Pollak, Peter; Papers apap368
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Peter Pollak Papers
1942-1987
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap368
4.05 cubic ft.
This collection documents political events and issues, predominantly from the early 1940s to the early 1970s, through publications collected by University at Albany graduate student Peter Pollak.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Peter G. Pollak at three different times in 2017.
Historical Note
A native of Gloversville, New York, Peter G. Pollak obtained his bachelor's degree from Oberlin College and later received his master's degree in Education in 1970 from SUNY Albany. He subsequently became a Ph. D student in Education at SUNY Albany. Pollak was active in the civil rights movement and was a VISTA (Volunteers in Service to America) anti-poverty volunteer in Atlanta before coming to SUNY Albany.
While in Albany, he continued to be engaged in activism on a community and broader level. He served as managing editor of The Albany Liberator, a weekly newspaper designed to serve the needs of the city's Arbor Hill and South End communities. The publication was owned and published by The Brothers, an area civil rights group. Pollak also was a member of the Albany Region/Capital District chapter of SDS (Students for a Democratic Society). In addition, he helped lead an unsuccessful fight to establish a day care center at the University in the early 1970s.
Following a career spent teaching, editing, and in business, Pollak became a self-published author. After living in the Capital Region of New York for decades he relocated to Elkridge, Md. for the final years of his life and died in October 2021 at age 78.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes political newspapers, pamphlets, and flyers collected by Peter Pollak as well as publications that were mailed directly to Pollak. These items document international, national, and local Capital Regional issues. Researchers may be interested in materials from the Capital District chapter of SDS (Students for a Democratic Society).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Underground press publications--periodicals; Student movements--United States; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Public opinion.; Students--New York (State)--Political activity.; Pollak, Peter G.; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.)
- "ABC's About Vietnam", Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "The Activist Reader", Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Agrarian Policies", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Akwesasne Notes", 1987 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
- "The Albany Student Press", 1967 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
- "The Albany Student Press", 1968 (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
- "The Albany Student Press", 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
- "The Albany Student Press", 1980 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
- "The Albany Voice", 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
- "Ally With Campus Workers", Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "American Civil Liberties Union", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "The American Independence Movement Newsletter", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "The American People's Historical Society", 1979 (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
- "Americans Before Columbus", 1980 (Oversized 1, Folder 8)
- "Amerikan Education and Profit", Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Angola: The Struggle for Liberation", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Anti-Draft Resolution", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Anti-War Resolution", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "An Appeal to The American Conscience", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "An Opening Statement on Open Admissions, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Arms and The Mind", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Attica Did Not Start Here Nor Will It End Here", 1971 (Oversized 1, Folder 9)
- "Bibliography on The War In Vietnam", Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 10)
- "Big Brother as a Holding Company", Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "The Black Man's Share of The 'Great Society'", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "The Bond", 1968 (Oversized 1, Folder 11)
- "The Blueing of America", 1942-1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Brief Summary of Election Results Related To The Peace Issue", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Bring The Troops Homes Now Newsletter", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "The Buddhists, The War, and The Viet Cong", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "A Call to Resist Illegitimate Authority", Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Cambridge Vote on Vietnam", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- "Capital District SDS Newsletter and Flyers", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "Carl Oglesby", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- "Challenge: The Revolutionary Newspaper", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "Challenge: The Revolutionary Newspaper", 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
- "The Channeling Memo", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- "China and The Cold War", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "China's War-Making Potential: An Appreciation", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "Chinese Aggression: Myth or Menace?", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- "Chinese Foreign Policy", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- "Citizen's Alliance", 1978 (Oversized 1, Folder 13)
- "Citizens Amicus Brief in Support of H. Rap Brown's Appeal from his Bail Restrictions", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- "The Cold War, Revisited and Re-Visioned", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- "Coming To Canada?", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- "Comments by Thich Nhat Hanh on Some Frequently asked Questions About Vietnam", Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "Common Sense", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- "Conduct Unbecoming Lieutenant on The Peace Line", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "Corporate Imperialism for The Poor", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- "A Correspondent Who Has Reported on Vietnam Since 1962 Sums Up-Not a Dove, But No Longer a Hawk", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- "Counter-Insurgency and The New Foreign Relations", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- "Courts and G.E. in Collusion, 1942-1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- "Crisis in Construction", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "The Cultural Revolution In China: A Socialist Analysis", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- "Demands of the Welfare Rights Movement to the New York State Legislature", 1942-1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- "Democracy In China", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- "De-Mystify The Establishment Standardized Test", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- "Detroit: The July Days", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- "The Development of The Liberation Movement", Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
- "A Divorce Trial in China", Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- "Do You Know These Facts? Do You Support Them?", 1967 (Oversized 1, Folder 14)
- "Draft Board Research", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- "Draft Counseling Service Pamphlet", 1942-1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- "The Drug Price Scandal", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- "The Dulocratic Review", Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
- "Economic Aspects of U.S. Imperialism", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- "The Effect of Inflation: Wages, Unemployment and Working Conditions", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- "El Malcrido: The Voice of The Farm Worker", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- "Excerpts from The Declaration of Former Resistance Fighters on The Present Situation in Southern Vietnam", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- "Excerpts of The Port Huron Statement", Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
- "The Exploitative Nature of The New York State Budget and Tax System", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- "Factsheet on The New McCarran Act", Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
- "Fear Neither Criticism Nor Self-Criticism, To Live Outside the Law You Must Be Honest!", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- "Fire!", 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
- "Flowers of Liberation", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- "Focus on Viet-Nam", Undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
- "For a Collective and Anti-Imperialist Struggle Against The Draft", Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
- "Forward", Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
- "Freedom", 1955 (Oversized 1, Folder 16)
- "Four Kentucky Miners Face Prison Terms", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- "From Conscience to Consciousness", Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
- "From Hanoi: Convoys Move by Night to Thwart Bombers", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- "The Garrison Society", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- "Geoffrey Reed Conklin", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- "Germ Warfare Research for Vietnam", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- "The Great Flint Sit-Down Strike Against G.M. 1936-1937", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- "The Great South Asian War: U.S. Imperial Strategy in Asia", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- "The Great Speckled Bira", 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 17)
- "A 'Green Beret' Blasts The War", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- "Green Mountain Quarterly", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- "The Green Piano", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- "The Guardian", 1968 (Oversized 1, Folder 18)
- "A Guide to Working Class History", Undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
- "The Hana Industrial Complex", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- "Health Rights News", 1975 (Oversized 1, Folder 19)
- "Hell No! National Black Anti-War Anti-Draft Union", Undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
- "H.I.R.E. Flyer", 1942-1987 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- "History as Indoctrination: A Critique of Palmer and Colton's History", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- "How to Make Slums and Create Barbarians", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- "Huey Newton: Huey on Anarchists and Individualists as Related to Evolutionary Struggle and The Black Liberation Movement", Undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
- "I.F. Stone's Weekly", 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- "In Peaceable Conflict", Undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
- "Indochina Chronicle", 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- "Industrial Worker", 1970-1971 (Oversized 1, Folder 20)
- "Industrial Workers of The World-Correspondence", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- "Inflation and Food", Undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
- "Information for Participants", Undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
- "Inscape", 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 21)
- "Intellectuals Must Serve The People", Undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
- "The International Committee of Conscience on Vietnam", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- "International Socialist Review", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- "Interviews: The International Bulletin", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- "Inter-University Committee for Debate on Foreign Policy", Undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
- "The Irish Rebel", 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 22)
- "IUE Local 301 Picket Line News", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- "Join An Anti-Automobile Demonstration", Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 23)
- "Join The People Who'll Never Join Today's Military", Undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
- "Just: Newsletter of The Community Legal Rights Foundation, Inc.", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- "The Kansas Free Press", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- "The Key to Peace", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- "Knickerbock News & Times Union Clippings", 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- "The Ku Klux Klan? George Wallace? Or The Freedom Movement?", Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
- "Labor and The South: Black Workers Set Against White-Strike Broken", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- "Learning From Chile: Resources for Teachers and Students", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- "The Left Under The Counterrevolution", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- "The Legacy of Slavery and The Roots of Black Nationalism", Undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
- "Legal Issues of U.S. Position in Vietnam", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- "The Legality of U.S. Participation in Defense of Vietnam", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 105)
- "Let Us Shape the Future", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- "Liberated Guardian", 1970 (Oversized 1, Folder 24)
- "Liberation News Service" (1 of 6), 1968-1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 25)
- "Liberation News Service" (2 of 6), 1968-1969 (Oversized 2, Folder 1)
- "Liberation News Service" (3 of 6), 1968-1969 (Oversized 2, Folder 2)
- "Liberation News Service" (4 of 6), 1968-1969 (Oversized 2, Folder 3)
- "Liberation News Service" (5 of 6), 1968-1969 (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
- "Liberation News Service" (6 of 6), 1968-1969 (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
- "Liberation News Service-Intro Page", Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
- "Liberation News Service-Letters and Copy", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 108)
- "Liberation News Service-List of Radical Publications and Where They Are Being Published", Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 6)
- "Liberation U.S.A. Newspaper of The American Liberation League", Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 7)
- "Long Live The Victory of People's War!", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- "MDS Newsletter", 1968-1969; Undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
- "Majority Report", 1973 (Oversized 3, Folder 1)
- "Mao Tse-Tung: Combat Liberalism", Undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
- "A Marxist Interpretation of Chinese History", Undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
- "The Meaning of Economic Imperialism", Undated (Box 1, Folder 113)
- "Military Conscription in The United States", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 114)
- "Mineral Wealth and Industrial Power: Communist China's Boasts Begin to Come True", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- "Mini-Truce in Vietnam", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 116)
- "Momentum", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 117)
- "Moon Shot: A Disorientation Handbook", Undated (Box 1, Folder 118)
- "The Morals of Extermination", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 119)
- "Movement", 1968-1969 (Oversized 3, Folder 2)
- "Movement", 1969-1970 (Oversized 3, Folder 3)
- "The Moratorium is a Cover, Not a Solution", 1942-1987 (Box 1, Folder 120)
- "Movement Fund-Raising Guide", Undated (Box 1, Folder 121)
- "The Mythology of Vietnam", Undated (Box 1, Folder 122)
- "NACLA: Report on The Americas", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 123)
- "NACLA's: Latins America and Empire Report", 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 124)
- "National Conference for New Politics", Undated (Box 1, Folder 125)
- "The National Liberation Front", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 126)
- "The New Citzen", 1976 (Oversized 3, Folder 4)
- "The New Foundation", 1969 (Oversized 3, Folder 5)
- "A New Look at U.S. Investments in Latin America", Undated (Box 1, Folder 127)
- "New Schools Exchange Newsletter", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 128)
- "The New South Student", 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 129)
- "New Roots: Self-Reliance for The Northeast", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 130)
- "New York Citywide Coordinating Committee of Welfare Groups", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 131)
- "New York Statewide Organization Lobbying Visit to Albany", 1942-1987 (Box 1, Folder 132)
- "Niagara SDS Regional Conference", Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 6)
- "No More Teacher's Dirty Looks", 1970; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 133)
- "Non-Violence is Not a Total Philosophy", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 134)
- "Notes From The Green Piano", Undated (Box 1, Folder 135)
- "Notes on The Theory of Imperialism", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 136)
- "Of Holy Disobedience", Undated (Box 1, Folder 137)
- "Old Mole", Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 7)
- "Okinawa Demonstration", Undated (Box 1, Folder 138)
- "On The Mechanism of Imperialism: The Case of Brazil", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 139)
- "Pacification in Vietnam", Undated (Box 1, Folder 141)
- "Paideia", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 142)
- "Paper Tiger", 1968; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "The Patriot: Peoples News Services", 1970 (Oversized 3, Folder 8)
- "Peace and Freedom Party", 1942-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- "People Against Racism: An Introduction to Who We Are", Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "The Phoenix", 1968 (Oversized 3, Folder 9)
- "Political and Organizing Principles for MDS", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "The Polytechnic", 1969 (Oversized 3, Folder 10)
- "Position on Selective Service", Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Post-Scarcity Anarchy", Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- "Poverty Law Report", 1979 (Oversized 3, Folder 11)
- "The Precondition to Desegregation-Black-White Unity", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- "Preventing The Peace", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "Progressive Perspectives", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- "The Project", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- "The Project Free School Schedule", 1942-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- "Putting-On The Poverty Program", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "Radical America", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "Radical America Catalog", 1971; 1973; 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- "Radical America-Correspondence", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- "The Radical Education Project", Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- "Radical Education Project: Study Guide Series", Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- "Radish", 1969-1970 (Oversized 3, Folder 13)
- "Radish", Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- "Rain", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- "RAT Subterranean News", 1968 (Oversized 3, Folder 13)
- "The Rebellion Against The Diem Regime 1957-1958", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- "Report on The War Crimes Tribunal", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- "Repression in The City MDS Organizes", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- "Researching The Governing Class of America", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "The Resistance Strategy", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- "The Responsibility of Intellectuals", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- "Resolution on Socialism", Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- "Revolution and Democracy", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- "Revolution and U.S. Aggression", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- "Revolutionary Youth Movement", Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 14)
- "Rights", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- "Rising Up Angry", 1969-1970; Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 15)
- "Rocky's Monumental Error, of the Billion-Dollar Misunderstanding", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- "Salisbury From Hanoi", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- "San Francisco Express Times", 1969 (Oversized 3, Folder 16)
- "Scarce Resources The Dynamic of American Imperialism", 1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- "SDS Bulletins", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 2 No. 1-7", 1967 (Oversized 4, Folder 1)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 2 No. 8-15", 1967 (Oversized 4, Folder 2)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 2 No. 16-27", 1967 (Oversized 4, Folder 3)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 2 No. 28-36", 1967 (Oversized 4, Folder 4)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 2 No. 37-46", 1967 (Oversized 4, Folder 5)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 3 No. 1-7", 1968 (Oversized 4, Folder 6)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 3 No. 8-14", 1968 (Oversized 4, Folder 7)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 3 No. 15-30", 1968 (Oversized 4, Folder 8)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 3 No. 30-38", 1968 (Oversized 4, Folder 9)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 4 No. 5-18", 1969 (Oversized 4, Folder 10)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 4 No. 19-25", 1969 (Oversized 4, Folder 11)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 4 No. 27-32", 1969 (Oversized 4, Folder 12)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 5 No. 2-7", 1969 (Oversized 4, Folder 13)
- "SDS New Left Notes Vol. 5 No. 8-11", 1969 (Oversized 5, Folder 1)
- "SDS New Left Notes Extra", 1942-1987 (Oversized 5, Folder 2)
- "The Second Front", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- "Seeds of Democracy: SCEF Projects In The South", Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- "Selective Service System Or, The Manpower Channelers", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- "The Significance of The State Department White Paper on Vietnam", 1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- "Sister: Connecticut's Feminist Publication", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- "Social Welfare Workers Movement-Correspondence", Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
- "Social Work Action for Welfare Rights", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- "A Socialist/Feminist View of The Organization of Production", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- "Solidarity", 1969 (Oversized 5, Folder 3)
- "Solidarity With The Peoples of Africa", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- "Some Facts About Vietnam", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "Something Else!", 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "South Carolina Black Students Attacked by Cops", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- "Southern Africa: The Facts, Crisis for American Policy", Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- "The Southern Patriot Vol. 25 No. 6-11", 1967 (Oversized 5, Folder 4)
- "The Southern Patriot Vol. 26 No. 1-10", 1968 (Oversized 5, Folder 5)
- "The Southern Patriot Vol. 27 No. 1-3", 1969 (Oversized 5, Folder 6)
- "The Southern Patriot Vol. 27 No. 5-7", 1969 (Oversized 5, Folder 7)
- "Speak Out", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- "Speak Out", 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Statement For No War Toys", Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- "The Strike News", 1970 (Oversized 5, Folder 8)
- "Students For a Democratic Society-Correspondence", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- "Students For a Democratic Society-News", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- "A Study of Domination and Repression: Mexico 1968" (Box 3, Folder 10)
- "The Sunday Ramparts", 1967 (Flat-file 1)
- "Support Black Revolutionaries", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- "Support Striking GE Workers U.S. Out of Vietnam Now, No Negotiations", Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- "Suppose They Gave a War and No One Came", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- "Sweet Fire Amerika Culture of Death", Undated (Oversized 5, Folder 9)
- "Talks At The Yenan Forum on Literature and Art", 1942 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- "The Tangled Asian Web", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- "Text of Statement on Vietnam War Made In Hanoi Interview by Premier Dang", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- "Thailand: An American Fortress In Asia", Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- "There's a Man Going Round Taking Names", Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- "This Is a Campus Organizer", Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- "Thoughts On The Movement: Who Does The Movement Move?", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- "Tri-City Free Press", Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- "The Trojan Horse", Undated (Oversized 5, Folder 10)
- "UAW Emergency Unemployed Rally", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- "The United States In Vietnam", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- "The University Continental Bank and Apartheid", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- "An Unnamed Paper", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- "Up Tight With The Draft?", Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- "The Urban Voice", 1969-1970 (Oversized 5, Folder 11)
- "The U.S. Rebuff To U Thant: The Untold Story", Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
- "U.S Relations With China", 1949 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- "The U.S. System and Vietnam: A Speech by Carl Oglesby Delivered at The Nov/65 March on Washington", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- "Veteran Stars and Stripes for Peace", 1967 (Oversized 5, Folder 12)
- "Vietnam Bulletin", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- "Vietnam Fact Sheet", Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
- "The Vietnam Lobby", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- "Vietnam: People's War or Negotiations?", Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
- "Vietnam Quiz", Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
- "Vietnam, a Selected Bibliography", Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
- "Vietnam: Setting The Moral Equation", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- "Vietnam Study Guide and Annotated Bibliography", Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
- "Vietnam: A Thousand Years of Struggle", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- "Visit To a Rural Commune", Undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
- "Vo Ng Uyen Giap: Analysis of The Vietnam War", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- "The War Blunders On: What Do We Do?", Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
- "A Web of Power", Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
- "Welfare Imperialism in Vietnam", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- "Which Way University Authority? Which Way Student Rights?", Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
- "Who Will Pay?", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- "Why Make Scapegoats of the Construction Workers When We Can Get Jobs and Reconstruct Our Community at the Same Time?, 1942-1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- "Will Your Child Go To College?", Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)